# Asadullah Farooqi

Software Engineer

+923111686184 asadullah.itcgcs@gmail.com

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Maher Inc, Lahore — Software Engineer

Feb 2019 - Present

I'm working on stylemepretty, ReactJS, Python.

## <u>Maher Inc</u>, Lahore — Full stack Engineer Internship

DEC 2018 - IAN 2019

I am working here on full-stack environment but Python Django and Angular are the mostly used Technologies in my job.

## **NHIIT**, Multan — Python Instructor

DEC 2016 - MAR 2017

During my short stay at Multan, I taught python to starters.

## **Akbar Computer Academy**, Loralai — IT Instructor

NOV 2015 - MAR 2016

I was an instructor of hardware and some other computer basics.

## **EDUCATION**

# Udacity, Intro to Deep learning with Pytorch

NOV 2018 - Present

# **Boys Degree College**, Loralai — *Fsc(Faculty of Science)*

MAR 2013 - AUG 2015

## **Farooqi Public High School**, Ziarat — *Matriculation*

MAR 2011 - AUG 2012

## **PROJECTS**

## **Inventory Web App** — asadliam.pythonanywhere.com

Inventory web app for wholesalers.

## Checkout my Github for my work.

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a self-taught, highly passionate Developer and hobbyist. I've used a vast amount of online resources to learn various aspects of computer science in which I have deep interest. My primary source of computer science knowledge has been the MIT Opencourseware and some other too.

I spend time on <u>Projecteuler.net</u>, <u>Hackerrank.com</u> and <u>Google foo.bar</u> to sharp my problem solving and coding skills which turns out to be a lot of fun. I also do mock interviews on <u>Pramp</u>.

My primary expertise is in Algorithms, advanced Python programming and writing Django/Angular/'Basic React' based web applications and apis, and also Ipython/Jupyter-notebook.

### **SKILLS**

Python, Django, REST-API, Flask, Git, JS/ES6, AngularJS, TypeScript, HTML5, CSS3, Basic C/C++, DS, Algorithm design and analysis, Bootstrap 4, Data Analysis with Pandas

#### Links

Portfolio
GitHub
LinkedIn
Twitter
Skype: asadullah.itcgsc

#### **LANGUAGES**

English, Urdu, Pashto, Persian (Farsi) basic